# **Rebecca Marriott**

# Data Analyst / Fullstack Software Developer

Norwich UK / Rebecca.marriott@outlook.com/ 07522569108

## Summary

I have a built up experience in a variety of different roles and industries during my career, however, my passion lies in Web development and specifically Data Analytics. I feel challenged and motivated to progress within this industry and I find the work fulfilling, with a particular interest in machine learning and AI. I have invested time in furthering my skill set by studying with Code Institute I have achieved my Full Stack Web Developer qualification. I am a reliable, versatile, and level-headed professional and I am capable of working effectively to tight deadlines and in high-stress situations. I collaborate well in a team but am also self-motivated to work alone. I am serious about working in the data analytics sector and furthering my career.

#### **Technical Skillset**

**Python** 

Libraries: pandas, matplotlib, numpy, Seaborn, plotly, scikit-learn, scipy

Power Bi

Tools: DAX, API, Power Query

**Frameworks** 

Streamlit, Bootstrap, Django, jQuery

SQL

Software: SQLite, MySQL

**Tableau** 

Visualizations , bins, joins, Calculated fields

**Jupyter Notebooks** 

live code, equations, visualizations, and text

**Excel** 

Tools: Pivot Table, Pivot Chart, VLOOKUP, HLOOKUP, VBA

Other Languages HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

Version Control GitHub, CodeAnywhere

#### **Portfolio Projects**

1. Stories Of WW2 - This is a website looking at some of the amazing stories of WW2 many had a major impact in turning the tide against the Nazis and helped the allies to win the war. These stories had a big impact on me showing the courage and bravery people injured to overcome one of the most brutal dictatorships in history. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS.

Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/stories-of-ww2">https://github.com/Becky139/stories-of-ww2</a>

2. **GOT Quiz** - This website is a quiz created to test your knowledge of the hit show Game Of Thrones that ran for 8 seasons from April 2001 until May 2019, set in the fictional kingdom of Westeros. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/GOT-Quiz">https://github.com/Becky139/GOT-Quiz</a>

3. **Battleship Game** - Battleship (also known as Battleships or Sea Battle is a strategy type guessing game for two players. It is played on ruled grids (paper or board) on which each player's fleet of warships are marked. Technologies used to build: Python

Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/Battleship">https://github.com/Becky139/Battleship</a>

- 4. **Mutts Cuts** Consider *Mutts Cuts Grooming*, a hypothetical start-up business whose only employee is its sole trader/owner. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, Python. Link to Github https://github.com/Becky139/mutts-cuts
- 5. Breast Cancer Prediction Thus, the goal is to classify whether the breast cancer is benign or malignant and predict the recurrence and non-recurrence of malignant cases after a certain period. To achieve this, we have used machine learning classification methods to fit a function that can predict the discrete class of new input. Technologies used to build: Jupyter Notebooks, Python, Streamlit.
  Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/Breast-Cancer-Prediction">https://github.com/Becky139/Breast-Cancer-Prediction</a>
- 6. SQL Data Clean Mini Project A small Project to show how to do some basic data cleaning using Microsoft SQL server.

https://github.com/Becky139/SQLDataClean

7. Covid Mini Project in SQL – A small Project using Microsoft SQL server to show soe queries to produce some basic visualizations.

https://github.com/Becky139/Covid-SQL

- 8. Bike Sales Mini Project in Excel A small project using excel to do some data cleaning and show some basic visualizations for bike sales data using Microsoft excel.

  Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/Bike">https://github.com/Becky139/Bike</a> Sales miniproject
- Airbnb Mini Project Tableau A small project showing how to use data in tableau to create some basic visualizations using some Airbnb data from Kaggle.
   Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/Airbnb\_Mini\_Project">https://github.com/Becky139/Airbnb\_Mini\_Project</a>
- 10. Data Analytics Survey PowerBI A small project using some data from a survey of data analysts from around the world. Creating data transform to do some data cleaning and some basic visualizations to create a dashboard.

Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/PowerBI-Survey">https://github.com/Becky139/PowerBI-Survey</a>

of Scotland)

# **Collaborative Projects**

**Hackathon: Stranger Bits**- Created as a team with a theme of Hack Hero a music quiz/game. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Becky139/Hack-hero">https://github.com/Becky139/Hack-hero</a>

### **Education**

| Jul 2023- Present   | Python Data Science with Pandas Master Course (Udemy)  |
|---------------------|--|
|                     | Work with Pandas, SQL Databases, JSON, Web APIs & more to master your real-world Machine Learning & Finance Projects   |
| Jul 2023 – Jul 2023 | Data Analyst Bootcamp (YouTube)  |
| Jul 2022 – Jul 2023 | Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)  Diploma in Full-stack Software Development (Accredited by the University West |

Jun 2021-Jan 2022

Cisco

CCNA

CCNP

Mar 2020-Mar 2021

**IT Career Switch Ltd** 

IT Technician Traineeship

1-year program

2021: CompTIA CYSA+ CS0-001

2021: CompTIA A+ 220-1001 & 1002

Sep 2001 - July 2003

**Lowestoft College** 

BTEC Sport and Leisure Diploma

Sep 1998 – July 2001

**Benjamin Britain High School** 

**GCSEs** 

**Work Experience** 

May 2019 – Present POSITION HELD:

**Group Lotus** 

**IT Network Engineer** 

- Worked on network monitoring repairs and maintenance
- Looked after the anti-virus, ensuring that it worked correctly and performed all security checks
- Prior to this, worked as part of the service desk team performing troubleshooting and customer service throughout the business

Nov 2019 – Apr 2019 POSITION HELD: JT Global

**Installation Engineer** 

- Worked on the gigabit project, working on installations in customer properties
  and adapting the installation to suit the customer's needs. This was both
  challenging and rewarding, as each property is different as well as the
  customer's ideas and needs
- Over two years' experience installing and testing fibre to the home and dealing on a daily basis with customers
- Experience in pulling and installing copper cables patch panels and making data and phone points

Sep 2007 – Sep 2016 POSITION HELD:

Army

**Team Leader** 

- Responsible for a storage unit containing millions of pounds-worth of kit, ensuring was safely and correctly stored
- Ordered any replacement kit needed and ordered parts for all the vehicles in the fleet
- On exercises, drove and maintained a variety of vehicles, providing support to front line troops
- Looked out for the new workers, ensuring they understood their role and supervised to make sure they worked safely and progressed themselves
- Nine years of military service across the UK Europe and worldwide

#### Additional Information/Interests

- From my time in the army I have traveled to many places and had a lot of opportunities to try many different sports I regularly watch football, rugby, and F1.
- I enjoy hiking and visiting different places and cultures
- I also enjoy spending time with my friends and family going to see shows, cinema

References are available on request.